<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.suchnsuch.Tangent</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Tangent</name>
  <developer id="@taylorhadden@mastodon.social">
    <name>Taylor Hadden</name>
    <url>https://everything-abridged.com/me/</url>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <summary>Record and connect your thoughts</summary>

  <description>
    <p>
      Tangent lets you write the way you think. Your thoughts are connected; Tangent lets you link to existing notes and make new ones with ease.
      Let your mind wander along the path of interest. Don't suppress tangential thoughts; embrace them. Key features include:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>[[Wiki-link]] linking to other files in your workspace by name.</li>
      <li>Horizontally-scrolling sliding panels for quickly moving back and forth along a trail of thoughts.</li>
      <li>A Map View of the links between notes created and followed during your current session.</li>
      <li>Note creation automation with support for creating notes within folders defined by wildcards.</li>
      <li>Full-workspace note search powered by a custom query language.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Tangent reads and writes plaintext notes using a loose interpretation of Markdown syntax.
      Text is rendered in a pseudo-WYSIWYG style, with formatting characters appearing only when you need them.
      Tangent supports bold, italics, headers, lists, links, images, todos, tags, inline code, block code with syntax highlighting,
      inline and block KaTeX math, color highlights, strikethrough, and comments.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.suchnsuch.Tangent.desktop</launchable>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#55dd84</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#1d9547</color>
  </branding>

  <recommends>
    <memory>200</memory>
    <display_length compare="ge">625</display_length>
  </recommends>

  <requires>
    <display_length compare="ge">450</display_length>
  </requires>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Thread view</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/thread-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Map view</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/blades-map-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Editing a note</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/markdown-syntax-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Wiki links showcase</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/wiki-links-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Focus mode</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/focus-mode-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Query language</caption>
      <image>https://www.tangentnotes.com/shots/flatpak/queries-dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://www.tangentnotes.com/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/suchnsuch/Tangent/issues/</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/suchnsuch/Tangent</url>

  <update_contact>k8ie_AT_mcld.eu</update_contact>

  <releases>
    <release version="0.10.2" date="2025-09-06">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Pressing escape now dismisses any active annotations or search highlights in a note.</li>
          <li>Completed or canceled Todos are now no longer crossed out while selected.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue that caused scrolling up in the [[Feed Lens]] to jump around obnoxiously.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.1" date="2025-08-23">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an issue where deleting text at the beginning of a line deleted text at the top of the document.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where section collapsed controls were impossible to click for indented lines.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where notes would scroll to their selection even when their selection hadn't changed.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2025-08-03">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for Collapsing Sections. Headers, lists, code, math, and front matter can all be collapsed. Collapsed state is kept persistent between sessions.</li>
          <li>Added an option to automatically collapse Front Matter.</li>
          <li>Made the Creation Rule name template tokens clickable buttons for easier editing.</li>
          <li>Added the Cmd/Ctrl+Alt+Shift+K shortcut for inserting wiki links with the selected text as the display text.</li>
          <li>Added support for adding links from the context menu.</li>
          <li>Exposed formatting toggles from the context menu.</li>
          <li>Added support for linking directly to header id links in markdown links.</li>
          <li>Added support for restoring selection and scroll position in notes between sessions.</li>
          <li>Added support for searching for and navigating to headers from the Cmd/Ctrl+O search menu.</li>
          <li>Made tag search not relative to the last name item, better matching user intuition.</li>
          <li>Updated to Electron 37.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where the note editor fallback feature wasn't correctly invoked.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where link data could be incorrect after editing links.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where closing inline formatting at the end of a link broke link parsing.</li>
          <li>Fixed several issues with selection and annotation initialization when opening notes.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2025-06-07">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Added support for link previews, with support for website previews, audio, video, and youtube links. Raw links on their own line are automatically previewed.</li>
          <li>Added support for displaying HTML with syntax highlighting.</li>
          <li>Hovering over wiki-links now show a preview of the note's contents.</li>
          <li>Changed scrolling cards in the Cards Lens to require <code>alt</code> by default. This can be changed within settings.</li>
          <li>Added support for Shifting Sections with Alt+Shift+Up/Down on Windows and Linux and ⌃⌥+Up/Down on Mac.</li>
          <li>Added an option to follow links with unmodified left clicks.</li>
          <li>Added an option to always autocomplete the full workspace path for Wiki Links.</li>
          <li>Added an option to control whether finished Todos are crossed out.</li>
          <li>Added support for selecting different code highlighting themes.</li>
          <li>Added support for searching within a single file.</li>
          <li>Added support for indenting headers, code blocks, math blocks, and quotes.</li>
          <li>Added support for unicode autocomplete in note titles.</li>
          <li>Added the List Lens and greatly improved the Card and Feed lenses.</li>
          <li>Switched to using the computer name instead of <code>hostname</code> when identifying a machine in workspace data.</li>
          <li>Added an option on linux and windows to use the native titlebar. Defaults to on for linux, off for windows.</li>
          <li>Added error and warning indicators for YAML parsing errors in Front Matter.</li>
          <li>Changed default Bold and Italics behavior so that underscores surrounded by text does not trigger formatting.</li>
          <li>Updated Electron to v35.4.0.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where query editor selection could be lost.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where you couldn't open a new query from the Map.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where query results could come out of order.</li>
          <li>Fixed HTML parsing to only start on valid tag names.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.4" date="2025-01-19">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated to Electron v34.0.0.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where autocomplete menus were not dismissed by clicking outside of the menu.</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where query refreshes could be caused by routine internal file changes within the `.tangent` folder.</li>
          <li>Removed donation links in compliance with new work terms.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.8.1" date="2024-11-02">
      <description>
        <p>Initial Flatpak release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
